Register of the Bertram David Wolfe papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Correspondence, 1913-1977 (Boxes 2-16)
  - Parkyn, G. W. (1), 1975 (Folder 11: 70)
  - Parrington, Vernon L. (1), 1928 (Folder 11: 71)
  - Partido Obrero de Unificacion Marxista (2), 1946 (Folder 11: 72)
  - Partisan Review (1), 1938 (Folder 11: 73)
  - Pashin, Nikolai S. (1), 1975 (Folder 11: 74)
  - Passin, Herbert (1), 1962 (Folder 11: 75)
  - Passivirts, Juhani (1), 1975 (Folder 11: 76)
  - Patterson, Margaret W. (1), 1957 (Folder 11: 77)
  - Payne, Stanley G. (4), 1968 (Folder 11: 78)
  - Pell, Senator Claiborne (1), 1974 (Folder 11: 79)
  - Pendleton, Lawson A. (3), 1974-1975 (Folder 11: 80)
  - Per/Se (2), 1967 (Folder 11: 81)
  - Pestkovsky, L. (1), 1926 (Folder 11: 82)
  - Petersen, William (6), 1968-1974 (Folder 11: 83)
  - Petrie, Dan (1), 1957 (Folder 11: 84)
  - Phalanx (2), 1966-1967 (Folder 11: 85)
  - Philbrick, Herbert A. (3), 1953 (Folder 11: 86)
  - Pipes, Richard E. (24), 1949-1972 (Folder 11: 87)
  - Pivert, Marceau (14), 1940-1944 (Folder 11: 88)
  - Ploss, Sidney (2), 1970 (Folder 11: 89)
  - Podhoretz, Norman (1), 1976 (Folder 12: 1)
  - Pohl, Frederick J. (2), 1945-1947 (Folder 12: 2)
  - Polish American Congress (1), 1945 (Folder 12: 3)
  - Polish Information Center (3), 1945 (Folder 12: 4)
  - Politics (1), 1949 (Folder 12: 5)
  - Pool, Ithiel (1), 1950 (Folder 12: 6)
  - Possony, Stefan T. (2), 1959-1965 (Folder 12: 7)
  - Post War World Council (2), 1943-1945 (Folder 12: 8)
  - Pound, Roscoe (2), 1949 (Folder 12: 9)
  - Powers, Rebecca (2), 1970 (Folder 12: 10)
  - Prager, Herman J., III (1), 1974 (Folder 12: 11)
  - Praja Socialist Party (1), 1953 (Folder 12: 12)
  - Preuves (1), 1956 (Folder 12: 13)
  - Princeton University (4), 1969-1973 (Folder 12: 14)
  - Pringle, First Lieutenant Robert W. (2), 1970 (Folder 12: 15)
  - Progressive (7), 1942-1945 (Folder 12: 16)
  - Providence Journal and Evening Bulletin (1), 1956 (Folder 12: 17)
  - Puerto Rico, University of (6), 1967 (Folder 12: 18)
  - Pundeff, Marin (1), 1962 (Folder 12: 19)
  - Purdue University (2), 1967 (Folder 12: 20)
  - Pushkarev, Sergei (2), 1971 (Folder 12: 21)
  - Putnam, Samuel and Riva (19), 1946-1954 (Folder 12: 22)
  - Quest (1), 1974 (Folder 12: 23)
  - Rabasa, Emilio O. (1), 1974 (Folder 12: 24)
  - Radical Humanist (1), 1954 (Folder 12: 25)
  - Radio Liberty Committee (3), 1972 (Folder 12: 26)
  - Raditsa, Bogdan (1), 1965 (Folder 12: 27)
  - Radkey, Oliver H. (6), 1969-1973 (Folder 12: 28)
  - Ram Singh (9), 1967-1972 (Folder 12: 29)
  - Rand School of Social Science (4), 1944-1948 (Folder 12: 30)
  - Rao, Raja (6), 1951-1953 (Folder 12: 31)
  - Rauh, Harriet F. (2), 1947 (Folder 12: 32)
  - Raymond, Colonel Edward A. (2), 1966 (Folder 12: 33)
  - Read, Cora J. (1), 1920 (Folder 12: 34)
  - Reagan, Governor Ronald (8), 1972-1975 (Folder 12: 35)
  - Reed, Alma (1), 1935 (Folder 12: 36)
  - Reeves, William J. (1), 1958 (Folder 12: 37)
  - Regler, Gustav (2), undated (Folder 12: 38)
  - Reider, Norman (1), 1971 (Folder 12: 39)
  - Reiff, Henry (1), 1963 (Folder 12: 40)
  - Religion in Communist Dominated Areas (1), 1968 (Folder 12: 41)
  - Relm Foundation (110), 1959-1969 (Folder 12: 42-43)
  - Rembao, Alberto (4), 1944 (Folder 12: 44)
  - Research Institute of America (1), 1957 (Folder 12: 45)
  - Reuben, William A. (1), 1968 (Folder 12: 46)
  - Reve, Karel van het (2), 1974 (Folder 12: 47)
  - Rexroth, Kenneth (20), 1939-1969 (Folder 12: 48)
  - Rhode Island, University of (1), 1958 (Folder 12: 49)
  - Riasanovsky, Nicholas V. (1), 1971 (Folder 12: 50)
  - Riesman, David (1), 1953 (Folder 12: 51)
  - Rio, Angel del (8), 1937-1949 (Folder 12: 52)
  - Ritter, R. C. (2), 1949 (Folder 12: 53)
  - Rivera, Diego (15), 1930-1940 (Folder 12: 54)
  - Rivera, Frida Kahlo de (8), 1933-1946 (Folder 12: 55)
  - Roberts, Craig (1), 1974 (Folder 12: 56)
  - Robertson, Deane (4), 1969 (Folder 12: 57)
  - Rochester, New York, University of (1), 1951 (Folder 12: 58)
  - Rockefeller Foundation (3), 1954-1962 (Folder 12: 59)
  - Rodman, Selden (2), 1949-1950 (Folder 12: 60)
  - Roeder, Ralph (1), undated (Folder 12: 61)
  - Rogger, Hans J. (2), 1967 (Folder 12: 62)
  - Rorty, James (5), 1950-1968 (Folder 12: 63)
  - Rose, Leo E. (6), 1976 (Folder 12: 64)
  - Rosenbaum, Kurt (1), 1962 (Folder 12: 65)
  - Rosenbaum, Sidonia C. (1), 1946 (Folder 12: 66)
  - Rosenberg, Harold (5), 1972 (Folder 12: 67)
  - Ross, Louis (1), 1922 (Folder 13: 1)
  - Rossiter, Clinton (1), 1956 (Folder 13: 2)
  - Rostow, Eugene V. (3), 1974-1976 (Folder 13: 3)
  - Rostow, Walt W. (2), 1970 (Folder 13: 4)
  - Rothrock Associates (2), 1969 (Folder 13: 5)
  - Rousselot, Representative John H. (2), 1975-1976 (Folder 13: 6)
  - Roux, Peter Robert (1), 1967 (Folder 13: 7)
  - Roy, Ellen (4), 1954-1957 (Folder 13: 8)
  - Roy, M. N. (2), 1949 (Folder 13: 9)
  - Royal Institute of International Affairs (6), 1948-1969 (Folder 13: 10)
  - Rozek, Edward J. (42), 1968-1976 (Folder 13: 11)
  - Rubel, Maximilien (3), 1966 (Folder 13: 12)
  - Rudy, Michael (2), 1971 (Folder 13: 13)
  - Russian Review (27), 1943-1972 (Folder 13: 14)
  - Russkaia Mysl' (1), 1974 (Folder 13: 15)
  - Ryan, William Harvey (5), 1973 (Folder 13: 16)
  - Ryskind, Morrie (3), 1973 (Folder 13: 17)
  - Sack, A. J. (1), 1948 (Folder 13: 18)
  - Sahl, Harry (1), 1952 (Folder 13: 19)
  - Salisbury, Harrison (3), 1973 (Folder 13: 20)
  - San Bernardino Valley College (1), 1967 (Folder 13: 21)
  - San Diego State College (3), 1968 (Folder 13: 22)
  - San Fernando State College (6), 1967 (Folder 13: 23)
  - San Francisco Chronicle (1), 1971 (Folder 13: 24)
  - San Francisco, University of (3), 1967-1969 (Folder 13: 25)
  - San Mateo (California) Times (2), 1966-1967 (Folder 13: 26)
  - Sanchez, Luis-Alberto (5), 1944-1949 (Folder 13: 27)
  - Sander, Hans-Dietrich (9), 1970-1971 (Folder 13: 28)
  - Santa Clara, California, University of (3), 1971 (Folder 13: 29)
  - Sapir, Boris (16), 1970-1973 (Folder 13: 30)
  - Sarmatia (1), 1945 (Folder 13: 31)
  - Saskatchewan Council of Public Affairs (1), 1963 (Folder 13: 32)
  - Scalapino, Robert A. (5), 1971-1974 (Folder 13: 33)
  - Schabert, Tilo (2), 1973 (Folder 13: 34)
  - Schapiro, J. Salwyn (1), 1954 (Folder 13: 35)
  - Schapiro, Leonard (15), 1956-1973 (Folder 13: 36)
  - Scharf, Max M. (2), 1972 (Folder 13: 37)
  - Scharlau, Winfried (1), 1966 (Folder 13: 38)
  - Scheibert, Peter (4), 1965-1971 (Folder 13: 39)
  - Scheyer, Lieutenant David (1), 1945 (Folder 13: 40)
  - Schlafly, Phyllis (1), 1976 (Folder 13: 41)
  - Schlesinger, Arthur, Jr. (7), 1948-1962 (Folder 13: 42)
  - Schmitt, Bernadotte (1), 1956 (Folder 13: 43)
  - Schnieder, Jim (1), 1969 (Folder 13: 44)
  - Schochet, Simon (1), 1969 (Folder 13: 45)
  - Schocken Books (2), 1970-1971 (Folder 13: 46)
  - Shcwartz, Julius (1), 1965 (Folder 13: 47)
  - Schwarz, Harry (4), 1965-1973 (Folder 13: 48)
  - Schwarz, Solomon and Vera (19), 1944-1966 (Folder 13: 49)
  - Scott, John (8), 1958-1974 (Folder 13: 50)
  - Seabury, Paul (1), 1976 (Folder 13: 51)
  - Sedova, Natalia (3), 1948-1949 (Folder 13: 52)
  - Segal, Rabbi Benjamin J. (3), 1971 (Folder 13: 53)
  - Sender, Ramon (4), 1948 (Folder 13: 54)
  - Senior, Clarence (4), 1938-1966 (Folder 13: 55)
  - Senn, Alfred (1), 1952 (Folder 13: 56)
  - Serdakovsky, Lev V. (9), 1969-1970 (Folder 13: 57)
  - Serge, Victor (3), 1941-1942 (Folder 13: 58)
  - Severance, Harold L. (1), 1969 (Folder 13: 59)
  - Shachtman, Max (2), 1968 (Folder 13: 60)
  - Shakeri, Khosrow (1), 1972 (Folder 13: 61)
  - Shapiro, Jane P. (2), 1968 (Folder 13: 62)
  - Sheehan, Joseph J. (1), 1971 (Folder 13: 63)
  - Sherby, Oleg (1), 1974 (Folder 13: 64)
  - Shideler, James H. (6), 1961-1965 (Folder 13: 65)
  - Shipman, Charles (2), 1964-1966 (Folder 13: 66)
  - Shockley, William B. (4), 1971-1973 (Folder 13: 67)
  - Shoop, Alan K. (2), 1971 (Folder 13: 68)
  - Shub, David (2), 1961-1971 (Folder 13: 69)
  - Sidorsky, David (1), 1971 (Folder 13: 70)
  - Siegman, Fred (1), 1926 (Folder 13: 71)
  - Silberstein, Richard (2), 1974 (Folder 13: 72)
  - Silverman, Lawrence F. (1), 1971 (Folder 13: 73)
  - Simon and Schuster (1), 1947 (Folder 13: 74)
  - Sinclair, Upton (3), 1952-1958 (Folder 13: 75)
  - Slaughter, M. Jane (4), 1975 (Folder 13: 76)
  - Slavic Review (56), 1961-1976 (Folder 13: 77)
  - Slavonic and East European Review (2), 1970 (Folder 13: 78)
  - Slusser, Robert M. (3), 1973-1974 (Folder 13: 79)
  - Smal-Stocki, Roman (2), 1950 (Folder 13: 80)
  - Smith, Dan Throop (1), 1974 (Folder 13: 81)
  - Smith, Edward Ellis (1), 1968 (Folder 13: 82)
  - Smith, Major General Ralph C. (1), 1975 (Folder 13: 83)
  - Smith College (2), 1950 (Folder 13: 84)
  - Smythe, W. Rodman (2), 1973-1974 (Folder 13: 85)
  - Snow, Edgar (2), 1956 (Folder 13: 86)
  - Socialist Party (India) (1), 1949 (Folder 13: 87)
  - Socialist Party (U.S.) (4), 1943-1944 (Folder 13: 88)
  - Solzhenitsyn, Aleksandr (4), 1975-1976 (Folder 13: 89)
  - Sorenson, Jay B. (4), 1969 (Folder 13: 90)
  - Sorich, Richard (1), 1954 (Folder 13: 91)
  - South Carolina, University of (1), 1969 (Folder 14: 1)
  - South Orange-Maplewood (New Jersey) Adult School (3), 1955 (Folder 14: 2)
  - Souvarine, Boris (67), 1955-1976 (Folder 14: 3)
  - Spectator (5), 1966-1967 (Folder 14: 4)
  - Sperber, Manes (14), 1954-1970 (Folder 14: 5)
  - Stanford University (50), 1962-1976 (Folder 14: 6)
  - Stanislaus State College (2), 1972 (Folder 14: 7)
  - Starr, Mark (1), 1976 (Folder 14: 8)
  - Staudenraus, Philip J. (2), 1967 (Folder 14: 9)
  - Stearn, Gerald (1), 1964 (Folder 14: 10)
  - Steere, Jonathan M. (2), 1948 (Folder 14: 11)
  - Stein and Day (82), 1964-1976 (Folder 14: 12)
  - Stenbock-Fermor, Elisabeth (5), 1969 (Folder 14: 13)
  - Stern, Frederick M. (1), 1955 (Folder 14: 14)
  - Steussy, R. E. (2), 1966 (Folder 14: 15)
  - Stevens, Vice Admiral Leslie Clark (5), 1952-1955 (Folder 14: 16)
  - Stevenson, William E. (1), 1947 (Folder 14: 17)
  - Stevinson, Chuck (1), 1976 (Folder 14: 18)
  - Stewart-Hill, Edwin H. (10), 1970-1972 (Folder 14: 19)
  - Stone, Al (1), 1969 (Folder 14: 20)
  - Strategic Review (5), 1974 (Folder 14: 21)
  - Strode, Hudson (3), 1944 (Folder 14: 22)
  - Struve, Gleb (16), 1959-1970 (Folder 14: 23)
  - Studies in Comparative Communism (2), 1973 (Folder 14: 24)
  - Sukhee, G. B. (1), 1955 (Folder 14: 25)
  - Sullivan, Mrs. (1), 1959 (Folder 14: 26)
  - Suny, Ronald Grigor (1), 1977 (Folder 14: 27)
  - Sutton, Antony C. (8), 1971-1974 (Folder 14: 28)
  - Sweet, John V. (2), 1967 (Folder 14: 29)
  - Swing, Raymond (1), 1955 (Folder 14: 30)
  - Switalski, John (1), 1954 (Folder 14: 31)
  - Switz, Theodore M. (2), 1941-1962 (Folder 14: 32)
  - Symes, Lillian (1), 1944 (Folder 14: 33)
  - Szasz, Alexander (1), 1949 (Folder 14: 34)
  - Tabb, Warner (1), 1917 (Folder 14: 35)
  - Taborsky, Edward J. (2), 1970 (Folder 14: 36)
  - Taft, Senator Robert A. (1), 1953 (Folder 14: 37)
  - Taggard, Genevieve (1), undated (Folder 14: 38)
  - Talmadge, Irving DeWitt (3), 1941 (Folder 14: 39)
  - Tamiment Institute (3), 1955-1956 (Folder 14: 40)
  - Tarsaidze, Alexandre (3), 1954-1970 (Folder 14: 41)
  - Taylor, George V. (1), 1968 (Folder 14: 42)
  - Taylor, Pauline B. (2), 1974 (Folder 14: 43)
  - Teller, Edward (4), 1973 (Folder 14: 44)
  - Temple, Martin (11), 1934-1967 (Folder 14: 45)
  - Tendler, Al (1), 1913 (Folder 14: 46)
  - Texas, University of (4), 1953 (Folder 14: 47)
  - Theen, Rolf H. W. (34), 1969-1973 (Folder 14: 48)
  - Thomas, Norman (23), 1938-1964 (Folder 14: 49)
  - Thomas Y. Crowell Company (1), 1960 (Folder 14: 50)
  - Thomson, Procter (1), 1973 (Folder 14: 51)
  - Time (2), 1962 (Folder 14: 52)
  - Times (London) (1), 1973 (Folder 14: 53)
  - Times of India (1), 1956 (Folder 14: 54)
  - Tolar, R. (1), 1970 (Folder 14: 55)
  - Tolstoy, Alexandra L. (1), 1969 (Folder 14: 56)
  - Toma, Peter A. (2), 1966 (Folder 14: 57)
  - Tompkins, E. Berkeley (3), 1973 (Folder 14: 58)
  - Tompkins, Stuart R. (8), 1952-1974 (Folder 14: 59)
  - Tongour, Stella (1), 1974 (Folder 14: 60)
  - Tonsor, Stephen (2), 1975 (Folder 14: 61)
  - Toor, Frances (4), 1939-1942 (Folder 14: 62)
  - Town Hall (4), 1945-1966 (Folder 14: 63)
  - Trager, Frank N. (3), 1966-1973 (Folder 15: 1)
  - Tri-Quarterly (11), 1967-1974 (Folder 15: 2)
  - Triska, Jan F. (1), 1968 (Folder 15: 3)
  - Tsiang, Ambassador Tingfu F. (2), 1955 (Folder 15: 4)
  - Tucker, Robert C. (12), 1968-1973 (Folder 15: 5)
  - Tvaruzka, Joseph J. (1), 1970 (Folder 15: 6)
  - Ukrainian Quarterly (5), 1945-1973 (Folder 15: 7)
  - U.S. Armed Forces Staff College (1), 1953 (Folder 15: 8)
  - U.S. Army Command and General Staff College (1), 1961 (Folder 15: 9)
  - U.S. Army War College (2), 1957 (Folder 15: 10)
  - U.S. Bureau of Customs (1), 1958 (Folder 15: 11)
  - U.S. Commission on Federal Paperwork (1), 1975 (Folder 15: 12)
  - U.S. Congress, House, Committee on Immigration and Naturalization (1), undated (Folder 15: 13)
  - U.S. Congress, Senate, Committee on Foreign Relations Subcommittee on Disarmament (3), 1956-1957 (Folder 15: 14)
  - U.S. Congress, Senate, Committee on Internal Security (3), 1970 (Folder 15: 15)
  - U.S. Department of State (16), 1928-1969 (Folder 15: 16)
  - U.S. Department of the Army (1), 1949 (Folder 15: 17)
  - U.S. Information Agency (22), 1953-1970 (Folder 15: 18)
  - U.S. Library of Congress (2), 1949 (Folder 15: 19)
  - U.S. National War College (10), 1948-1963 (Folder 15: 20)
  - U.S. Naval Academy (3), 1960 (Folder 15: 21)
  - U.S. Navy, Behavioral Sciences Group (1), 1963 (Folder 15: 22)
  - U.S. News and World Report (1), 1953 (Folder 15: 23)
  - U.S. Office of Censorship (2), 1943 (Folder 15: 24)
  - U.S. Office of Inter-American Affairs (1), 1944 (Folder 15: 25)
  - U.S. Office of War Information (3), 1945 (Folder 15: 26)
  - U.S. Postmaster, Linden, New Jersey (2), 1967 (Folder 15: 27)
  - U.S. Postmaster, New York (2), 1963-1964 (Folder 15: 28)
  - University Center in Virginia (4), 1960 (Folder 15: 29)
  - Urban, G. R. (18), 1965-1972 (Folder 15: 30)
  - Vaillant, George C. (1), 1941 (Folder 15: 31)
  - Valentin, Curt (1), 1947 (Folder 15: 32)
  - Vandenberg, Senator Arthur M. (1), 1948 (Folder 15: 33)
  - Vanguard Press (2), 1948 (Folder 15: 34)
  - Vanger, Milton I. (2), 1967-1968 (Folder 15: 35)
  - Varga, Monsignor Bela (2), 1951-1953 (Folder 15: 36)
  - Venturi, Franco (1), undated (Folder 15: 37)
  - Vernadsky, George (2), 1943-1956 (Folder 15: 38)
  - Viereck, Peter (13), 1953-1974 (Folder 15: 39)
  - Viking Press (1), 1959 (Folder 15: 40)
  - Villard, Oswald Garrison (3), 1945-1948 (Folder 15: 41)
  - Vinas Martin, Angel (1), 1977 (Folder 15: 42)
  - Virginia, Medical College of (1), 1960 (Folder 15: 43)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review (1), 1941 (Folder 15: 44)
  - Vishniak, Mark (1), 1965 (Folder 15: 45)
  - Vivas, Eliseo (14), 1973 (Folder 15: 46)
  - Vogue, Comtesse de (1), 1952 (Folder 15: 47)
  - Volin, Lazar (1), 1952 (Folder 15: 48)
  - Vol'skii, Nikolai and Valentina (26), 1957-1970 (Folder 15: 49)
  - Vorse, Mary Heaton (1), undated (Folder 15: 50)
  - WLW (radio station) Cincinnati (2), 1947 (Folder 15: 51)
  - Wadia, J. B. H. (1), 1960 (Folder 15: 52)
  - Wagner, Mayor Robert F. (1), 1973 (Folder 15: 53)
  - Waite, Robert G. L. (1), 1956 (Folder 15: 54)
  - Wakin, Bertha (1), 1963 (Folder 15: 55)
  - Walker, A. A. (1), 1967 (Folder 15: 56)
  - Walker, Richard L. (9), 1964-1973 (Folder 15: 57)
  - Walkin, Jacob (3), 1955-1959 (Folder 15: 58)
  - Walkinshaw, Robert B. (1), 1947 (Folder 15: 59)
  - Wallace, Frank (2), 1969 (Folder 15: 60)
  - Wallick, Franklin (1), 1947 (Folder 15: 61)
  - Walsh, Sister Margaret V. (2), 1974 (Folder 15: 62)
  - Walsh, Warren B. (4), 1946-1974 (Folder 15: 63)
  - Walt, General Lewis W. (1), 1971 (Folder 15: 64)
  - Walter-Verlag (2), 1963-1968 (Folder 15: 65)
  - Wang, Peter Y. H. (1), 1959 (Folder 15: 66)
  - Ward, Robert E. (1), 1975 (Folder 15: 67)
  - Warth, Robert D. (2), 1972 (Folder 15: 68)
  - Washington Post (1), 1965 (Folder 15: 69)
  - Washington (State) University (23), 1948-1974 (Folder 15: 70)
  - Wasserman, Jac (2), 1974 (Folder 15: 71)
  - Wasson, R. Gordon (3), 1952-1970 (Folder 15: 72)
  - Waterman, Dorothy (1), 1949 (Folder 15: 73)
  - Watson, Arthur K. (2), 1969 (Folder 15: 74)
  - Wauters, Arthur (1), 1948 (Folder 15: 75)
  - Weaver, Mrs. Henry (1), undated (Folder 15: 76)
  - Weeks, Albert L. (6), 1966-1968 (Folder 15: 77)
  - Weil, Felix J. (5), 1949-1973 (Folder 15: 78)
  - Weil, Irwin (2), 1967 (Folder 15: 79)
  - Weinstone, William (1), 1920 (Folder 15: 80)
  - Welter, Peter W. (3), 1975 (Folder 16: 1)
  - Werner, Maxentius E. (4), 1965-1968 (Folder 16: 2)
  - Wesson, Robert G. (5), 1972-1973 (Folder 16: 3)
  - West, Rebecca (3), 1953-1977 (Folder 16: 4)
  - Western Politica (1), 1966 (Folder 16: 5)
  - Weyl, Nathaniel (6), 1968-1971 (Folder 16: 6)
  - Whitcomb, John M. (1), 1958 (Folder 16: 7)
  - White, Theodore H. (1), 1958 (Folder 16: 8)
  - Whitfield, Stephen J. (3), 1971-1975 (Folder 16: 9)
  - Whitman College (4), 1969-1970 (Folder 16: 10)
  - Wilder, Elizabeth (1), 1942 (Folder 16: 11)
  - Wildman, Allan (4), 1967 (Folder 16: 12)
  - Wiles, Peter (1), 1962 (Folder 16: 13)
  - Wilkins, Roy (1), 1968 (Folder 16: 14)
  - William, Maurice (1), 1947 (Folder 16: 15)
  - Williams, Duncan (6), 1973-1974 (Folder 16: 16)
  - Williams, T. Desmond (1), undated (Folder 16: 17)
  - Willis, Dr. Charles D. (2), 1973 (Folder 16: 18)
  - Wilson, Edmund and Elena (16), 1940-1974 (Folder 16: 19)
  - Winslow, E. M. (1), 1960 (Folder 16: 20)
  - Witonski, Peter (8), 1974-1975 (Folder 16: 21)
  - Wittfogel, Karl A. (25), 1947-1976 (Folder 16: 22)
  - Wohl, Paul (2), 1968 (Folder 16: 23)
  - Wolfe, Ella (Mrs. Bertram D.) (87), 1921-1952 (Folder 16: 24-25)
  - Woodward, C. Vann (2), 1972 (Folder 16: 26)
  - World Affairs Council of Rhode Island (1), 1947 (Folder 16: 27)
  - World Affairs Council of San Joaquin County, California (3), 1969 (Folder 16: 28)
  - World Fellowship (1), 1941 (Folder 16: 29)
  - World Union (2), 1969 (Folder 16: 30)
  - Woytinksy, Wladimir and Emma (13), 1956-1965 (Folder 16: 31)
  - Wraga, Natalie (5), 1967-1971 (Folder 16: 32)
  - Yarmolinsky, Avrahm (2), 1975 (Folder 16: 33)
  - Yedlin, Tova (2), 1966 (Folder 16: 34)
  - Yergin, Daniel (1), 1975 (Folder 16: 35)
  - Yim, Louise (1), 1947 (Folder 16: 36)
  - Yost, Ambassador Charles W. (2), 1970 (Folder 16: 37)
  - Young Men's Christian Association (1), 1945 (Folder 16: 38)
  - Young People's Socialist League (1), 1971 (Folder 16: 39)
  - Young Women's Christian Association (2), 1940-1946 (Folder 16: 40)
  - Yugoslavia, Poslanstvo (U.S.) (1), 1975 (Folder 16: 41)
  - Zander, Lambert G. (2), 1971 (Folder 16: 42)
  - Ziemer, Otto (1), 1921 (Folder 16: 43)
  - Zigrosser, Carl (1), 1937 (Folder 16: 44)
- Speeches and Writings, 1914-1976 (Boxes 16-54)
  Drafts and printed copies of books, articles, speeches, lectures, reports, radio broadcasts, translations, and book reviews by Bertram D. Wolfe, with correspondence, notes, and reviews relating to them, arranged chronologically by date of publication or writing.
  - Comment on Leonard B. Schapiro, "The Political Thought of the First Provisional Government," and Oskar Anweiler, "The Political Ideology of the Petrograd Soviet,", undated; Typescript and printed copy. (Folder 16: 45)
  - "The Conquest of Power,", undated
    The conception of this unpublished work changed over a period of years. Some chapters have been published in Marxism: One Hundred Years in the Life of a Doctrine (1965), in An Ideology in Power: Reflections on the Russian Revolution (1969), or as journal articles; other chapters are unpublished. Some chapters were published under different titles. Chapters are in typescript unless otherwise noted.
    - Preliminary and miscellaneous leaves (Folder 16: 46)
    - Introduction (Folder 16: 47)
    - "'Neither Peace nor War'" (Folder 17: 1)
    - "Nationalism and Internationalism in Marx and Engels" (Folder 17: 2)
    - "Prelude to War" (Folder 17: 3)
    - "'No Country to Defend'" (Folder 17: 4)
    - "Lenin Has Trouble with Marx and Engels" (Folder 17: 5)
    - "Consultation with Clausewitz" (Folder 17: 6)
    - "War Is the Womb of Revolution" (Folder 17: 7)
    - "In Time of War Beware of Peace" (Folder 17: 8)
    - "Peace Terms for a Revolutionary War" (Folder 17: 9)
    - "To the Finland Station" (Folder 17: 10)
    - "The Sovereign Remedy" (Folder 17: 11)
    - "Our Time of Troubles" (Folder 17: 12-13)
    - "The Road to War" (Folder 17: 14-15)
    - "The Collapse of the International" (Folder 17: 16-17)
    - "Nationalism or Internationalism?" (Folder 18: 1)
    - "Pacifism, Defencism, or Defeatism?" (Folder 18: 2-3)
    - "Science or Utopia?" (Folder 18: 4-5)
    - "French Socialism or 'the German Theory?'" (Folder 18: 6-7)
    - "'A Party of a New Type'" (Box-folder 19: 1-2)
    - "Lenin's Idea of the Class War", Typescript and mimeograph. (Folder 19: 3-4)
    - "How Lenin Prepared for August 1914" (Folder 19: 5-6)
    - "Lenin and Inessa Armand" (Folder 19: 7-8)
    - "Backwardness and Industrialization" (Box-folder 20: 1-2)
    - "War Comes to Russia" (Folder 20: 3)
    - "War Comes to Russia-in-Exile" (Folder 20: 4-5)
    - "Autocracy without an Autocrat" (Folder 20: 6-7)
    - "Petticoat Government" (Box-folder 21: 1)
    - "Rasputin at the Court" (Folder 21: 2)
    - "The Second World Congress and Negotiations with the European Delegations" (Folder 21: 3)
    - "The Debates at the Second World Congress" (Folder 21: 4)
    - "The National and Colonial Questions and the Comintern's Initial Policy in the East" (Folder 21: 5)
    - "The Split in the Socialist Parties" (Folder 21: 6)
    - "March 1921: Misadventure in Germany" (Folder 21: 7)
    - "Lenin Builds His Machine" (Folder 21: 8)
    - "Lenin: The Russian Background" (Folder 21: 9)
    - "Leninist Norms" (Folder 21: 10)
    - Notes, Holograph and typescript. (Folder 21: 11-13)
    - Notes, Holograph and typescript. (Folder 22: 1-3)
  - "Death and Laughter,", undated; Typescript (Folder 22: 4)
  - "The Fate of Soviet Science,", undated; Typescript (Folder 22: 5)
  - Lecture on Maksim Gorkii, undated; Typewritten notes (Folder 22: 6)
  - "Military Collaboration, 1919-1930,", undated; Typescript (Folder 22: 7)
  - "Prospects for Change in Soviet Society and Policy," speech, Tamiment Institute, New York City, undated; Typewritten notes (Folder 22: 8)
  - "Russian Revolution: Promise and Performance," speech, undated; Handwritten notes (Folder 22: 9)
  - "Social Democracy Votes War Credits: Civil Peace and Sacred Union,", undated; Typescript (Folder 22: 10)
  - "Trotsky and Stalin: A Struggle for Power,", undated; Typescript (Folder 22: 11)
  - Untitled memoir on Iosif Stalin, undated; Typescript (Folder 22: 12)
  - Untitled writing on peaceful coexistence, undated; Notes (handwritten and typewritten) and typescript (Folder 22: 13)
  - Untitled writing on Soviet power system, undated; Typescript (Folder 22: 14)
  - "The Ideal State: An Attempted Application of the Principles of Ethics to the Social Organization," undergraduate essay, College of the City of New York, 1914 May; Typescript (Folder 23: 1)
  - "The Moorlands: An Impression," poem, Call (New York), 1918 May 10; Printed copy (Folder 23: 2)
  - Debate with M. J. Michel of the Socialist Labor Party on trade union policy, 1920s; Typewritten transcript (Folder 23: 3)
  - "The Heroism of Sandino and Pessimism of Scott Nearing," Daily Worker?, 1920s; Printed copy (Folder 23: 4)
  - "Rusia en 1924" (Russia in 1924), series of articles in Spanish, El Democrata, Typescript (incomplete) and printed copy (incomplete) (Folder 23: 5)
  - How Class Collaboration Works, pamphlet, 1926; Printed copy (Folder 23: 6)
  - Our Heritage from 1776: A Working Class View of the First American Revolution (with Jay Loveston and William F. Dunne), pamphlet, 1926; Printed copy (Folder 23: 7)